ARI DECTER-FRAIN

PhD Student - Cornell Policy Analysis and Management

■ agd75@cornell.edu — 🎓 aridecterfrain.com — 🗘 aridf — in aridecterfrain — 🛩 adecterfrain

SUMMARY

I am a versatile and collaborative problem-solver. I am fulfilled by rigorous work that promotes social good. I can contribute to any team by drawing on practical experience in leadership and product development, combined with broad knowledge of the social sciences and an ever-growing toolkit of computational research methods.

EDUCATION

Cornell University

08/2019 - Present

PhD Policy Analysis and Management (PAM)

Ithaca, NY, USA

• Relevant Coursework: Econometrics; Microeconomics; OOP and Data Structures

London School of Economics and Political Science

2016 - 2017

MSc Inequalities and Social Science (Distinction)

London, UK

- Dissertation: Patterns of Precarious Employment Among Migrants to the United Kingdom
- Honors: Hobhouse Memorial Prize for Best Overall Performance with Distinction
- Relevant Coursework: Causal Inference from Observational Data; Welfare Analysis and Measurement; The Politics of Inequality and Redistribution; Multidisciplinary Approaches to Inequality

University of Winnipeg

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Arts (Honors) Psychology (GPA 4.44/4.50)

Winnipeg, MB, CA

• Honors: Chancellors Gold Medal for the Highest Standing in the Arts (2016); Valedictorian for the class of 2016 Faculty of Arts, Undergraduate Research Award in the Social Sciences (\$4000, 2014); John and Elizebeth Coté Award for Excellence in Research Methods (\$1500, 2014)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Manager

08/2018 - 05/2019

Multi Health Systems (MHS) - Technology R&D

Toronto, ON, CA

- Assumed product ownership of a workplace mental health screening assessment, championed the social and business importance of worker well-being; achieved a five-fold increase in unit sales.
- Supervised a team of two software developers and a data scientist to support distributors' API integrations; developed, tested, and released new features.
- Conducted a top-down revision of the product's business model and profitability; streamlined company product portfolio and improved future profitability.

Research Analyst

11/2017 - 08/2018

Multi Health Systems (MHS) - Innovation Hub

Toronto, ON, CA

- Designed and implemented a minimum viable product for an automated custom assessment-builder application; instigated company transition from a per-unit to a subscription revenue model.
- Built an R-based psychological assessment scoring and reporting system; first company use of dynamic reporting in a product, first use of R as a production-level coding language.

• Developed an algorithm to automatically shorten assessment products; Reduced length of an emotional intelligence test by 80 percent while maintaining integrity of key results.

Laboratory Manager / Research Assistant

University of Winnipeg - Moral Psychology Lab

08/2013 - 04/2016 Winnipeg, MB, CA

- Developed leadership and collaboration skills while supervising research assistants and thesis students conducting research in moral and political psychology.
- Taught experimental design, academic writing, and data analysis to research assistants and honors thesis students.
- Designed, conducted, analysed and reported on 10+ research projects, including linguistic analyses using LIWC, online and lab experiments, meta-analyses, and literature reviews.

Researcher

09/2013 - 04/2016

Public Interest Law Centre of Manitoba (PILC)

Winnipeg, MB, CA

- Developed research and strategic analysis skills while writing and presenting briefings to senior lawyers as part of the 2014 Needs For and Alternatives To review of Manitoba Hydros preferred hydroelectric development plan.
- Gained versatility as a researcher by studying a wide range of topics, including endangered species, employment accessibility legislation, and cost-benefit methodology.

PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

Decter-Frain, A., Frimer, J.A. (2017). Agentic and communal rhetoric in the quest for political popularity. Talk presented at the European Association of Social Psychology (EASP) conference.

Decter-Frain, A., Vanstone, R., Frimer, J. A. (2017). Why and how do moralistic groups create heroes? In Allison, S. T., Goethals, G. R., Kramer, R. M. (Eds.). Handbook of heroism and heroic leadership. New York: Routledge.

Decter-Frain, A., Frimer, J.A. (2016). Impressive words: Linguistic predictors of public approval of U.S. Congress. Frontiers in Psychology: Personality and Social Psychology. doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.00240

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Coding Software R, Python for data; HTML, CSS for web; PostgreSQL for databases Rstudio, Jupyter Notebooks, LaTeX, pg Admin 4, Microsoft Office, SPSS

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

Board Member and Volunteer

09/12 - Present

Sholem Aleichem Community

Winnipeg, MB, Canada

Consulting Team Leader

180 Degrees Consulting

11/16 - 04/17 London, UK

• Led a team of six LSE graduate students to produce a report on emerging skills gaps in the UK; provided key advice for a Smart City revitalisation project in Thamesmead, a London borough.

Oxford Spring School of Advanced Research Methods

04/17 Oxford, UK

Oxford Department of Politics and International Relations

• Studied alongside PhD students from around the world to learn R, the principles of data visualization, and causal inference statistical methodologies.